Cortney Davis Papers
Cortney Davis Papers
circa 1960-2007
Davis, Cortney, 1945-
8 linear ft.
Correspondence, writings, fan mail, journals, juvenilia, memorabilia of the nurse practitioner and poet.
2607307
Biographical History
Cortney Davis (1945- ) is an American nurse practitioner, author and lecturer. She attended Western Connecticut State University, graduating magna cum laude with a B.A. in 1983 and an M.A. in 1989, and is a registered nurse (RN) and Advanced Practice RN (APRN) as well as a board-certified Adult Nurse Practitioner. Ms. Davis is also a published author, having worked as staff writer and freelance editor for Nursing Spectrum Magazine as well as publishing books, articles, essays and poetry.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Cortney Davis Papers consist of correspondence, writings, and memorabilia.
Correspondence includes personal, business, and fan mail. Writings include several years' worth of Davis' journals as well as juvenilia, poetry, speeches, and notes and assignments from her undergraduate and graduate school days. Memorabilia relates to poetry readings and to workshops (both given and attended), along with a small amount of miscellaneous material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Writings and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Science and medicine; Davis, Cortney, 1945-; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Medical personnel, Writings of.; Medical practice -- Poetry.; Nurses' writings, American.; Nurse and patient -- Literary collections.; Nurses -- Literary collections.; Nursing -- Literary collections.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Speeches (documents); Poems.; Nurses.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Cortney Davis, 2007.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Allen, Dick (Box 1)
  - Allen, Lori (Box 1)
  - Armer, Sondra (Box 1)
  - Cramer, Steven (Box 1)
  - Deppe, Ted (Box 1)
  - Fadiman, Mark (Box 1)
  - Gioia, Dana (Box 1)
  - Hemphill, Betty (Box 1)
  - Hicks, Tom (Box 1)
  - Grosholz, Emily (Box 1)
  - Honemann, Debbie (Box 1)
  - Lindsay, Meg (Box 2)
  - Lux, Tom (Box 2)
  - Metras, Gary (Box 2)
  - Menashe, Samuel (Box 2)
  - Miller-Laino, E. J. (Box 2)
  - Morgan, Fred (Box 2)
  - Murch, Muriel (Box 2)
  - Mysko, Madeleine (Box 2)
  - Ogden, Hugh (Box 2)
  - Olds, Sharon (Box 2)
  - Parker-Gibson, Necia (Box 2)
  - Pensak, Susan (Box 2)
  - Perel, Jane Lunin (Box 2)
  - Pollard, Norah (Box 2)
  - Pushcart Prize (Box 2)
  - Ratzan, Richard (Box 2)
  - Richman, Elliot (Box 2)
  - Rust, Laurel (Box 2)
  - Sands, Jean (Box 2)
  - Schaefer, Judy (Box 2)
  - Selgin, Peter (Box 2)
  - Shipley, Vivian (Box 2)
  - Sternlieb, Barry (Box 2)
  - Stamatien, Claire (Box 2)
  - Starkman, Elaine (Box 2)
  - Taylor, Nancy (Box 2)
  - Vahanian, Tilla (Box 2)
  - Valentine, Jean (Box 2)
  - Volk, Brenda (Box 2)
  - miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - fan mail (Box 2)
  - correspondence with editors publishers 2002-2007 (Box 3)
  - correspondence about grants and grant applications 1990-2005 (Box 3)
- Writings
  - Journals
    - “Change Journal”, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - “Dream Journal”, 1981-1998 (Box 4)
    - “Dream Journal”, 1998-2002 (Box 5)
    - “Vacations”, 1987-1999 (Box 5)
  - Juvenilia (Box 5)
  - Poetry, 1977-1984 (Box 5)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 5)
  - Undergraduate and graduate courses notes and assignments (Box 5)
- Memorabilia
  - Poetry readings, 1993-2007 (Box 6)
  - Workshops given, 1992-2007 (Box 7)
  - Workshops attended, 1993-1997 (Box 8)
  - Misc. (Box 8)